--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请登陆 http://www.hdcmct.com
影片压制: 暮雨潇潇   招募Q号: 76846146
片名:不可饶恕
她是一名美丽的女子 原本应该前途远大
所以当她下嫁威廉莫尼时 她母亲才会为之心碎
因为威廉是个杀人放火无恶不做的恶徒
而且酗酒成性
不过她的死却不是威廉造成的
而是不幸罹患天花 时值1878年
"怀俄明州 大威士忌1880年"
不 求求你...
No, please! No! Please!
戴维!
Davey!
- 快过来 - 求求你 不要
- Come a running, lad! - Please don't!
- 住手 - 我要在你身上烙印 臭婊子
- Stop it! - Brand you like a damn steer, bitch!
求求你 住手
No, please!
戴维 抓住那婊子...
Hold the bitch, Davey! Go on, hold her!
快抓住她 否则我一刀割掉她的奶子
Goddamn it, Davey. Hold her or I'll cut her tits off!
快去找瘦皮猴
Go get Skinny! Quick!
麦克 住手
Mike, don't!
瘦皮猴
Skinny!
你觉得很好笑?
Do you think it's funny?
瘦皮猴 快拿枪来
Skinny! Get the gun!
放开她 牛仔
Get off of her, cowboy.
- 他们不让你摆平这件事? - 你也了解瘦皮猴这个人
- They wouldn't let you settle it? - You know how Skinny is.
他说他要一枪毙了他们
He says he's gonna shoot them.
我说"不行" 他说 "去找小比尔来评理"
I says, "You can't." He says, "Get Little Bill in here to settle this."
我说"他在睡觉" 但他不在乎
I says, "He's sleeping." But he says he don't care.
你再不来 他就要大开杀戒了
In another five minutes, he's gonna shoot them boys.
她活得成吗?
Is she gonna die?
死不了
She's gonna live.
她没有偷东西 甚至没碰他的口袋
She didn't steal nothing. She didn't even touch his poke.
只不过在看到他的小老二时
But when she seen he had a teensy little pecker...
忍不住笑了出来 她年纪小 不懂事嘛
...she gave a giggle. That's all. She didn't know no better.
吊死他们 小比尔
You can hang them, Little Bill.
到办公室去拿鞭子来
Step over to the office and get the bullwhip.
他们禽兽不如你只打算抽他们一顿?
A whipping? That's all they get after what they done?
- 鞭刑非同小可 - 但是他们...
- It ain't no little thing. - But what they done...
艾莉丝!
Alice!
闭嘴!
Shut up!
- 小比尔 抽他们一顿没有办法解决这件事 - 是吗?
- A whipping ain't gonna settle this. - Oh, no?
这是我和那个被剌伤的妓女荻莱菈费兹杰罗间的合约
Here's a contract between me and Delilah Fitzgerald, the cut whore.
我把她从波士顿带来 负责她的一切开销
I brought her from Boston, paid her expenses and all.
这只合约代表了我的投资
And I got a contract that represents an investment of capital.
财物
Property.
现在是受损财物了
Damaged property.
他们这种行为相当于残害别人的牲口
Like if I was to hamstring one of their cow ponies.
你认为没有人愿意搞她了?
You figure nobody'll wanna fuck her now, right?
那当然!
Hell, no!
至少不愿为此花钱
Leastways they won't pay to do it!
也许她能充当清洁女佣 但谁愿意花钱搞一个千疮百孔的妓女?
She could clean up the place, but nobody's gonna pay good money...for a cut-up whore!
你们是从拜提牧场来的?
You boys are off the Bar T.
你们有自己的马吗?
Got your own string of ponies?
有 我有四匹
Yeah, I got four.
我有六匹
Six.
你不希望闹上法庭吧?
Guess you'd just soon as not have a trial, no fuss?
不希望
No, sir.
那好
All right.
动刀的人是你
You did the cutting.
今年秋天我要你赶五匹马来给瘦皮猴
Come the thaw, you bring in five ponies and you give them over to Skinny.
五匹?
Five?
而你嘛...
And you...
你赶两匹来
You bring in two.
- 听到没? - 听到了
- You give them over, you hear? - Yes, sir.
鞭子来了
Here's the bullwhip, Bill.
也许暂时用不上
Maybe we don't need this whip now.
要是到了春天 瘦皮猴还没有拿到马的话...
Let me tell you, come the spring, and Skinny don't have those ponies...
- 我会来找你们的 - 你甚至不打算抽他们?
- I'm gonna come looking for you. - You ain't even gonna whip them?
艾莉丝 我也很狠狠的敲了他们一笔
Well, I fined them instead, Alice.
他们做出这种事赔几匹马就算了?
For what they done, Skinny gets some ponies! That's it?
不公平 小比尔...
That ain't fair, Little Bill.
不公平
That ain't fair!
今天晚上见的血光还不够吗?
Haven't you seen enough blood for one night?
艾莉丝...
Hell, Alice...
他们不是好吃懒做的流浪汉或坏蛋
...it ain't like they was tramps or loafers or...
而是几个卖力工作的傻瓜
...bad men. They were just...hardworking boys that was foolish.
- 若他们道德沦丧 - 像妓女吗?
- If they was wicked in a regular way... - Like whores?
艾莉丝 去照顾荻莱菈
Alice, tend to Delilah.
去吧
Go ahead.
我有85块
I got $85.
我不知道
I don't know.
若荻莱菈不在乎 我们又干嘛这么激动?
If Delilah doesn't care, what are we getting so riled up about?
我们让那些傻瓜骑在我们身上
Just because we let them smelly fooIs ride us like horses...
并不表示可以让他们为所欲为
...don't mean we gotta let them brand us like horses.
我们虽然是妓女 但天可怜见...
Maybe we ain't nothing but whores, but we...
我们不是马
By God, we ain't horses!
我有112块
I got $112.
就这么多了
That's everything.
那你呢 费丝?
How about you, Faith?
我有200
$200.
240块
$240.
费丝 你怎么会有这么多钱?
Jesus, Faith, what you been doing?
是不是帮瘦皮猴做特别服务?
You been giving Skinny something special?
她笑了
She laughs.
我们几个人的钱加起来...
With what Kate got, and Silky got some, and mine and Little Sue...
不够的
It ain't enough.
现在也许还不够
Not yet, maybe.
你看起来实在不像是个天杀的冷血杀手
You don't look like no son-of-a-bitching, cold-blooded assassin.
你说什么?
Say what?
你大概就是威廉莫尼吧?
My guess is you're calling yourseIf Mr. William Munny.
你认错人了 先生
You have me confused with someone else, mister.
在雷克郡一枪毙了查理派柏的人是你吧?
Same one as shot Charlie Pepper up in Lake County?
爸...
Pa! Hey, Pa!
什么事 儿子?
What's up, son?
又有两头猪病倒
Two more hogs got the fever.
你杀了查理派柏 对吧?
Didn't you shoot Charlie Pepper?
你也在密苏里抢火车时杀了威廉哈维
You killed William Harvey and robbed that train over in Missouri.
等等
Hold on, mister.
儿子 你先把病猪赶到一边去
Son, you get those hogs separated there.
潘妮 去帮你哥哥
Penny, why don't you help your brother?
那头猪也病了
That one's sick, too.
咱们进去谈
We'll talk inside.
你是比特瑟豪的侄子?
So you're Pete Sothow's nephew?
我还以为你是我的旧日仇家上门来杀我的
I thought maybe you'd come to kill me for something I'd done in the old days.
那也不一定
I could have.
别激动
Easy.
我想也是
I guess maybe so.
我刚说了你实在不像是个冷血杀手
Like I was saying, you don't look like no meaner-than-hell, cold-blooded damn killer.
也许我不是
Maybe I ain't.
比特叔说你是世界上最凶残冷血的龟孙子
Yeah, well Uncle Pete says you was the meanest goddamn son of a bitch alive.
若我想找人联手大开杀戒
And if I ever wanted a partner for a killing...
你是最狠的一个
...you were the worst one.
也就是说找你就对了
Meaning the best.
因为你冷血无情也不知恐惧为何物
On account as you're as cold as the snow...and you don't have no weak nerve nor fear.
比特这么说?
Pete said that?
没错
Yeah, he did.
我也是个杀手 但是因为年纪还轻所以杀的人没你多
I'm a damn killer myself, except I ain't killed as many as you...because of my youth.
大家都叫我库费小子
Schofield Kid, they call me.
为什么?
Why?
你是库费人?
You from Schofield?
不 因为我用的是
No, it's on account of my...
史密斯威森库费款的手枪
...Schofield model Smith & Wesson pistol.
怎么样?
How about it, Will?
什么怎么样?
How about what?
想不想当我的伙伴?
How about being my partner?
我要向北越过尼勃拉罗河到怀俄明州去
I'm heading up north in through Niobrara up to Wyoming.
杀两个为非作歹的牛仔
Gonna kill a couple of no-good cowboys.
为什么?
For what?
因为他们把一个女士划得面目全非
For cutting up a lady.
他们用刀割她的脸
They cut up her face.
挖出她的眼睛 割掉她的耳朵
Cut her eyes out, cut her ears off.
然后割掉她的奶子
Hell, they even cut her teats.
天啊
Jesus.
干这一票能赚一千块
$1,000 reward, Will.
咱们一人分五百
$500 apiece.
爸 我赶不动那些该死的猪
Pa, I can't move those damn pigs!
嘴巴放干净点
Watch your cussing now, will you?
你尽力吧 去打点水梳洗一下
Do the best you can with it. Go to the pump and get cleaned up.
快去
Come on.
小子 我已经不可同日而语
I ain't like that anymore, Kid.
以前那样蛮干 都是酒精作祟
It was whiskey done it as much as anything else.
我已经十多年来滴酒不沾
I ain't had a drop in over 10 years.
我太太...
My wife, she...
治好我酗酒的毛病
cured me of that cured me of drink and wickedness.
你看来混得不太得意
Well, you don't look so prosperous.
你可以用你那份赏金帮她买套新衣服
Hell, you could buy her a new dress with your half.
杀了他们你可以帮你太太买件漂亮的...
We could kill them two. You could buy your wife a fancy...
她已经死了
She's passed on.
什么?
What?
死了快三年了
Been gone near three years now.
别告诉别人赏金的事 我可不希望别人跑来跟我分一杯羹
Don't tell anyone about the reward. I don't need no other gunman trying to collect.
咱们这儿很少有人来
We don't see no one out here.
你若改变心意的话再来找我
If you change your mind, maybe you could catch me.
我要向西走山路再向北到怀俄明
I'll be riding due west for the Western Trail headed north into Wyoming.
咱们来赶猪吧
Come on, let's separate those hogs.
又有两头猪病倒了
Two of them others I think they got the fever.
你们两个怎么这么久才来?
Took you boys a while.
若再过两天不来我就要去找警长了
A couple more days and I was going to call on the sheriff.
你说怎么样?
How about that?
河水水位高涨 我们过不来
The river was all swelled up. Couldn't cross it.
我想也是 瞌睡虫 把马牵走
I bet. Sleepy, get them horses on the livery.
尼尔 带一匹到后面去
Neil, take that one over around the back.
这匹马真漂亮
Now here's a beauty.
我已经给你两匹了 这匹不是你的
You got two of mine. This one here ain't yours.
咱们走着瞧吧
We'll see about that.
浑蛋 快滚!
Bastards! Get out of town!
快走开...
Get out of here!
你们这些变态的龟孙子
You are very sick sons of bitches!
永远别想回来 屠夫
Don't come back, butcher!
这匹马是我带来给被我兄弟割伤的那位小姐
This here pony...I brung for the lady, the one my partner cut.
这匹马比别的马都好
She's the best of the lot.
比我给他的马好多了
Better than the ones I gave him.
她能卖了这匹马
She can sell her...
怎么处置都行
...or do what she wants.
一匹马?
A pony?
她被你们害得面目全非 你居然给她一匹烂马?
She ain't got no face left. You're gonna give her a mangy pony?
这匹马不烂
She ain't mangy, ma'am!
滚出去
Get out of here!
我们不用你来施舍
We don't need your goddamn charity!
滚出去 永远不要回来
Get out of our town and don't come back!
滚出去
Get out of our town!
爸以前会杀人吗?
Did Pa use to kill folks?
佩妮 你妈一定很喜欢我送她的花
Penny, I could tell your ma liked those flowers I gave her.
牠太久没有套马鞍 已经不习惯了
She ain't hardly a saddle horse no more, Pa. She ain't used to the feel.
好好照顾妹妹
You take care of your sister now, son.
有必要的话杀几只鸡来吃 别忘了把生病的猪隔离开来
Kill a few chickens if you have to, and keep the hogs with the fever separate.
有什么问题就去奈德罗根家找二树莎莉
If you have any problem, you go see Sally Two Trees at Ned Logan's.
我也好一阵子没骑马了
Ain't hardly been in the saddle myseIf in a while.
这匹马是藉机会报复我已前做过的错事
This horse is getting even with me for the sins of my youth.
在遇见你们死去的妈之前
In my youth, before I met your dear departed ma...
我年少无知 常常虐待动物
...I used to be weak and given to mistreating animals.
这匹马和猪栏里的猪...
This horse and those hogs over there...
都是在藉机报复我 我以前满嘴脏话
...are getting even with me for the cruelty that I inflicted.
马儿一不乖就被我打得半死
I used to be able to cuss and whip a horse like this...
但是你们的妈让我明白我是错的
...but your ma, rest her soul, showed me the error of my ways.
我两个礼拜后就回来了
I'll be back in a couple of weeks.
别忘了 你们死去的妈会在天上保佑你们
Remember how the spirit of your dear departed ma watches over you.
- 你的钱是哪儿来? - 我们没有钱
- Where'd you get that money? - We ain't got any money!
- 你告诉那些牛仔说你们有钱 - 那是骗他们的
- You told them cowboys you had! - We was lying!
骗他们的?
Lying?
万一他们上门来收钱怎么办?
What will you do when somebody comes to collect?
你要跟他们搞一千次吗?
You gonna hump them? You gonna hump them a thousand times?
那些高价杀手知道你们没钱一定会抓狂的
The kind of people that come after $1,000 won't tolerate you not having it!
他们可不会划花你们的脸蛋就消气
They won't just cut up your face a little!
你们这些蠢婊子
You stupid bitches.
蠢婊子
可恶!
Shit!
该死的! 老天爷!
Damn it! Jesus!
打到手指头了?
Get your finger?
嗨 瘦皮猴
Hello, Skinny.
差点被你吓死
Man, you snuck up on me.
喜欢这栋房子吗?
What do you think of her?
听说屋顶是你自己盖的?
I heard you done the roof yourself.
屋顶?
Roof?
这栋房子几乎全是我一个人盖的
Jesus, Skinny, I did practically the whole damn thing myself.
罗伯特家的小毛头帮我运了几趟木头 但就这样
The Roberts boy carried some wood for me, but that's all.
那些木头是干嘛用的?
What's all that wood?
是我要用来盖阳台的 这样傍晚就能坐在阳台上
I'm building a porch here so I can sit of an evening and smoke my pipe...
抽烟斗 喝咖啡 欣赏夕阳
...and drink coffee and watch the sunset.
你大老远跑来是来看我的房子吗?
Came all the way out here just to see her?
我手下那些烂婊子...
Them whores...
这两个礼拜拼了命搞那些路经本镇的牛仔
...been humping all them cowboys that been to town the last two weeks.
真他妈的
Shit.
咱们这儿有铁路大亨也有养牛大亨
We got our railroad barons. We got cattle barons.
你会成为本镇史上第一位撞球大亨
You're gonna be the first billiard baron.
她们还跟那些牛仔说
They been humping up and telling every bowlegged one of them...
只要他们杀了伤害荻莱菈的那两个家伙
...they're paying $1,000 to whatever son of a bitch...
就能拿到一千块
...kilIs the two boys that cut up Delilah.
那些牛仔不是要赶牛到堪萨斯和夏安吗?
Those cowboys are riding that beef down to Kansas and Cheyenne?
多久? 一个星期吗?
How long? All week?
我也是昨晚才听说的
I didn't hear nothing till last night myself.
现在这件事搞不好已经传到德州了
The word's probably got all the way down to Texas by now.
该不会有人大老远从德州杀过来了吧?
Nobody's gonna come clear from Texas.
那些妓女真的有钱吗?
You sure they got all that money?
那些女人都是骗死人不偿命 我问过了 她们根本没钱
Women can lie. Knock them around, ask where it is, they say they got none.
但是五个人凑一凑说不定还真的凑得出来
They could've squirreled away that much, the five of them.
也许吧
Maybe.
多少钱?
That much?
你可以把那两个牛仔赶走
You could run off them two cowboys.
我也能赶走那些妓女
I could run off them whores.
我想那两个人早就逃之夭夭了
I guess they'll just up and run anyhow, them two.
他们会留在拜提牧场
They'll stay out there at the Bar T.
跟朋友待在一块儿
Close to their friends.
比尔 搞不好根本不会有人来
Oh, shit, could be nobody won't come at all.
我得走了 这栋房子盖得不错
Well, got to go. I like your house.
我八成是眼花了...
Well, I'll be...
是威尔
It's Will.
- 快进屋里来坐坐 - 奈德
- Come on in the house out the sun. - Ned
莎莉 你去照顾威尔的马
Sally, see to Will's horse.
莎莉
Sally
你来干嘛? 威尔
What you doing here?
来看看你
Just thought I'd drop in on you.
威尔 我们已经改邪归正了
We ain't bad men no more.
我们现在是农夫
Shit, we're farmers.
要杀他们不难 不过得赶在他们去德州之前
Should be easy killing them, supposing they don't go on down to Texas first.
威尔 你有多久没对人开枪了? 有十年了吧?
How long has it been since you fired a gun at a man, Will? Nine, ten years?
十一年
Eleven.
还说不难?
Easy, huh?
咱们年轻的时候杀人就已经不容易了
I don't know that it was all that easy even back then.And we was young and full of beans.
若他们对不起你
I mean, if you was mad at them...
咱们杀了他们还情有可原
...if they'd done you wrong, I could see shooting them.
我们以前也曾经为了赚钱杀人
We done stuff for money before, Ned.
那是我们一厢情愿的想法
We thought we did.
这两个家伙做了什么好事?
All right, so what'd these fellows do?
打牌作弊? 偷牛? 侮辱有钱人? 究竟做了什么?
Cheat at cards? Steal some strays? Spit on a rich fellow? What?
- 不 他们把一个女人的脸划花了 - 什么?
- No, they cut up a woman. - What?
割伤她的脸 挖出她的眼睛 剁掉她的手指 割掉她的奶子
Cut her face, cut her eyes out, cut her fingers off, cut her tits.
大概只有她的阴部没糟殃
Everything but her cunny, I suppose.
真他奶奶的过份
I'll be dogged.
那两个人死有余辜
Guess they got it coming.
威尔 你知道的
Of course, you know, Will...
若克劳蒂雅还在世 你不会淌这趟浑水
...if Claudia was alive, you wouldn't be doing this.
我家那两个小家伙就麻烦你照顾了
I don't suppose you'd look in on my youngsters next week?
帮他们隔离病猪
Got some hogs they're trying to separate.
你这趟要去多久?
How long are you gonna be?
两个星期吧
Two weeks, I guess.
那个小子是什么德性?
This Kid, what's he like?
怎么分钱?
Three ways?
看来你还留着你那把来福枪嘛
I see you still have that Spencer rifle.
而且我现在还是能百步穿杨
And I can still knock the eye out of a bird flying, too.
天啊 威尔
Jesus, Will.
他应该在这附近
He must be moving right along.
我想明天应该会碰到他
We'll come across him tomorrow, I reckon.
我已经睡习惯我的床了 这里实在比不上家里
Got to get used to my bed. This ain't going to be like no home.
让我念念不忘的可不只是我的床
That ain't the only thing I'll miss, I'll tell you.
对不起
Hell, I'm sorry.
别放在心上 没事
Don't fret it. It ain't nothing.
你就这样跟我来了 她一定很不高兴吧?
She don't like it much, does she...you riding off with me?
莎莉
Sally
她狠狠的瞪了我一眼
Gave me the evil eye.
莎莉是印地安人
You know, Sally's Indian and...
印地安人本来就比较冷漠
...lndians ain't over-friendly.
我不怪她
I don't blame her.
我也不会因为这件事而记恨她
I ain't gonna hold it against her.
她当年就认识我了
She knew me back then.
对我当年的恶行了然于心
She knew what a no-good son of a bitch I was.
她只是不能接受我洗心革面的事实
She ain't allowing that I changed.
她不明白我已经变了
She don't realize I ain't like that no more.
- 女人就是这样 - 我已经变了 奈德
- You know women. - I ain't the same, Ned.
克劳蒂雅让我改邪归正 她帮我戒除酗酒等恶习
Claudia, she straightened me up. Cleared me of drinking whiskey and all.
我接下这笔生意
Going on this killing...
并不表示我会重新走上歧途
...don't mean I'm gonna go back to the way I was.
我这么做是因为缺钱
I just need the money.
要有钱才能让孩子们过好日子
Get a new start for them youngsters.
还记得那个被我一枪轰掉脑袋的赶牛郎吗?
Remember that drover I shot through the mouth...and his teeth came out the back of his head?
我偶尔会想起他
I think about him now and again.
他不该落得死无全尸
He didn't do anything to deserve to get shot.
我酒醒之后不记得他做过什么恶事
At least nothing I could remember when I sobered up.
你当年是个疯狂的龟孙子
You was one crazy son of a bitch.
没人喜欢我
No one liked me.
大家都会以为我会一时萌生恶念杀了他们
The boys all thought I'd shoot them out of pure meanness.
你已经变了
You ain't like that no more.
伊格恨我入骨
Eagle, he hated my guts.
波拿巴也对我敬而远之
Bonaparte didn't think too much of me, either.
我想昆西也差不多
Quincy neither, I reckon.
昆西总是胆战心惊的注意我的一举一动
Quincy used to just watch all the time.
我说过...
Like I said...
你已经变了
...you ain't like that no more.
没错
That's right.
我现在是个凡夫俗子
I'm just a fellow now.
和别人没什么不同
I ain't no different than anyone else.
不再特别
No more.
我只想知道是哪个狗娘养的杀了他
All I want to know is what son of a bitch shot him is all.
是英国人吗?
Was it one of them John Bulls?
不 先生
No, sir.
我认为那个杀手是个法国人 至少看来是如此
The would-be assassin is a gentleman of French ancestry. Or so it would seem.
我不想冒犯任何人
I don't wish to give offense, when I observe...
但法国人一向嗜杀成性 只不过他们的枪法烂得可以
the French are known to be a race of assassins who can't shoot worth a damn.
当然 在场的法国人例外
Any Frenchmen in the present company are excluded, of course.
上面说那小子叫做吉多...
Says here a fellow by the name of Guiteau. G-U-l-T...
一听就知道是英国人
Sure as hell sounds like a John Bull to me.
我无意唐突
Well, sir, again, I don't wish to give offense...
但我还是认为这个国家该选出
...when I suggest that this country should select...
一个国王或女王而不要选总统
...a king or even a queen, rather than a president.
因为人们在下手剌杀皇室之前
One isn't that quick to shoot a king or a queen.
总是会三思的
The majesty of royalty, you see.
先生 你嘴上说无意冒犯任何人
Maybe you don't wish to give offense, sir...
但你说的话我们听起来还真不是滋味
...but you are giving it pretty thick.
美国才不需要什么女王
This country don't need no queens whatsoever, I reckon.
- 事实上 我听说女王... - 闭嘴 乔
- When I heard about queens... - Shut up, Joe.
你哪根筋不对啦? 这小子...
What the hell's wrong with you, Thurston? This dude...
这小子就是英格兰鲍伯
Might be that this dude here is English Bob.
他专门为铁路公司追杀中国佬
He's the one that works for the railroad shooting Chinamen.
说不定他正在等某个发疯的牛仔动手拿枪
Might be he's waiting for some cowboy...
好一枪毙了那个牛仔
...to touch his pistol so he can shoot him down.
是真的吗?
Is that a fact, mister?
你真的是英格兰鲍伯?
You English Bob?
雉鸡鸡
Pheasants.
咱们去打雉鸡鸡
Let's shoot some pheasants.
十发
Ten shots.
一只雉鸡鸡一块钱
And let's say $1 a pheasant.
我为女王开枪 你爱为谁开枪就为谁开枪
I'll shoot for the queen, and you for...whomever.
咱们八比一
That's eight for me and one for you.
你要给我七块美金
That comes to $7.
你这个英国佬...枪法还真不错
Pretty damn good shooting...for a John Bull.
你一定是因为总统受伤而心神大乱...
No doubt your aim was affected by your grief...
所以失了准头
...over the injury to your president.
也许是受到气候或距离的影响吧
It's the climate that does it. That, and the infernal distances.
什么东西?
Does what?
人们才会想要枪杀位高权重的人
Induces people to shoot persons in high places.
这个国家真野蛮
You know, it's a savage country, really.
20年间已经有两位总统被枪击
That's the second one they shot in 20 years.
杀有钱人很不文明
It's uncivilized shooting persons of substance.
谢谢
Thank you.
打扰一下
Pardon me, gentlemen.
法律规定 两位在此停留期间
Local ordinance obliges you to surrender all sidearms...
必须将随身武器交给有关单位代为保管
...to the proper authorities for the duration of your visit.
有关单位?
Proper authority?
年轻人 我以人格保证
I can assure you, young man...
我和我同伴身上并没有携带任何武器
...that neither my companion nor I carry firearms on our person.
我们只希望各位能善意的对待我们
We rely upon the goodwill of our fellow man and the...
而且爬虫类能放我们一马
...forbearance of reptiles.
没带武器个屁
Unarmed, my ass.
天啊 真是热死了
Christ, it's hot.
热天挨枪子儿总比冷天好
If I'm going to get shot, I'd rather it was hot than cold.
天冷的时候受伤更痛
Everything hurts me more when it's cold.
- 天冷的时候打到姆指... - 闭嘴 肥仔
- You hit your thumb in the cold... - Shut up, Fatty!
- 我只是说... - 克莱德回来了
- I only said... - Clyde's back.
- 跟小比尔一起回来? - 没有
- Is Little Bill with him? - No.
狗屎
Shit.
- 我的猎枪清干净了吗? - 清干净也上膛了
- You boys clean my Remington? - Cleaned and loaded.
小比尔死到哪儿去了?
Where's Little Bill, for Christ's sake?
在家盖他的阳台
Building his damn porch.
盖阳台?
Building his porch?
你希望在热天中枪还是冷天?
If you got shot, would you like it better on a hot or cold day?
我不会挨枪子儿的
I ain't going to get shot.
他会来吧?
He's coming, ain't he?
那当然
Of course he's coming.
我才刚装过子弹 你在做什么?
I just loaded that. What're you doing?
别人办事我不放心
I don't trust nobody to load my guns for a shooting.
他怎么说?
What'd he say?
小比尔什么都没说 只说他要盖他的阳台
Bill didn't say nothing. He said he was building his porch.
你们看过他的阳台没?
You seen that thing?
全都装好子弹了
It was all loaded.
你只有一只手却有三把手枪!
You got three pistols and you only got one arm!
我只是不希望没子弹了而送命
I just don't want to get killed for lack of shooting back.
他的阳台盖得歪七扭八
He don't have a straight angle on that whole damn porch!
事实上 整栋房子都是歪七扭八
Or the whole house, for that matter!
我从没看过这么蹩脚的木工
He is the worst damn carpenter.
他啥都没说?
He didn't say nothing?
他只问了他们的长相
Asked what they looked like.
他虽然很悍却是个很烂的木工
Maybe he's tough but he sure ain't no carpenter.
也许他也没那么悍
Maybe he ain't so tough.
他看起来害怕吗?
Seem like he was scared?
小比尔会害怕?
Little Bill? Him scared?
我们从来没看他跟这种狠角色单挑过
We've never seen him up against any like these ones.
他们是杀手
Killers.
小比尔在堪萨斯和德州混过
Little Bill comes out of Kansas and Texas, boys.
他在蛮荒地带工作过
He worked them tough towns.
人家只是好奇嘛
Just wondered.
任何人都可能害怕
Anybody could be scared.
各位 他不害怕
He wasn't scared, boys.
但他是个蹩脚的木工
He just ain't no carpenter.
皇室的王者风范会消弭人们剌杀他们的意图
There's a dignity in royalty. A majesty that precludes the likelihood of assassination.
若你用枪指着国王或女王
If you were to point a pistol at a queen...
双手会颤抖到失控
...your hands would shake as though palsied.
我不会用枪指着任何人
I wouldn't point no pistol at nobody.
这倒是明哲保身之道
Always a wise policy.
但我保证 万一你真这么做
But if you did, I can assure you, if you did...
皇室成员的威严会让你打消杀人的念头
...the sight of royalty would cause you to dismiss all thoughts of bloodshed.
你会...这该怎么说呢...
You would stand, how should I put it?
敬畏之感油然而生
In awe.
至于总统嘛...
Now, a president...
人人得而诛之
Well, why not shoot the president?
- 不用找钱了 - 谢谢
- Keep the change. - Thank you
再说说艾莉丝的事
This Strawberry Alice person, tell me again.
你向前经过葛瑞利啤酒屋和撞球间
Down the street and across to Greely's Beer Garden and Billiards Parlor.
说要找艾莉丝和打一局撞球
Ask for Alice, say you want a game of billiards.
撞球?
Billiards?
不想打也没关系?
Even though I don't wish to play?
没错 他们早在七八年前就把撞球台砍了当柴烧
No matter. They burned the table in '78 for firewood.
我明白了...
Quite right.
布夏先生 喝杯茶...
Mr. Beauchamp, I think a cup of tea...
嗨 鲍伯
Hello, Bob.
诸位 这是英格兰鲍伯
Boys, this here is English Bob.
这下完蛋了
Shit and fried eggs.
咱们好久没见 鲍伯
Been a long time.
中国佬杀光了吗?
Run out of Chinamen?
小比尔 我以为你已经死了
I thought that you were dead.
你把落腮胡刮掉了
I see you've shaved your chin whiskers off.
是啊 喝汤不方便
I was tasting the soup two hours after I ate it.
我听说你
Actually, what I heard was you...
烂醉如泥从马背上摔下来
...fell off your horse. Drunk, of course.
结果把脖子摔断了
And that you broke your bloody neck.
鲍伯 这谣言我也听过
I heard that one myself, Bob.
连我都以为自己嗝屁了
Hell, I even thought I was dead...
但后来发现我只不过是去了内布拉斯加
...till I found out I was just in Nebraska.
你朋友是谁?
Who's your friend?
在下布夏
W.W. Beauchamp.
这是小比尔戴吉特
This is Little Bill Daggett.
和他的朋友
And friends, of course.
纽顿海斯和艾比林的小比尔?
From Newton, Hays? From Abilene?
正是他本尊
In person.
你也在铁路公司做事? 布夏先生
You work for the railroads, too, Mr. Beauchamp?
不...我是爬格子的
I write.
写信?
Letters?
比尔 他是写书的
Books, Bill. Books.
事实上...
Actually...
他在帮我写自传
...he's my biographer.
换做是我 我就不会这么做了 布夏先生
I wouldn't do that if I were you. Mr. Beauchamp
只不过是一本书
It's only a book.
书?
A book?
这表示你们两个识字啰?
That means you boys can read.
也看得懂要你们缴械的告示牌
That means you saw the signs outside of town...saying surrender your firearms.
但是你告诉安迪说
But, like you told young Andy...
你们没有带武器 对不对?
...you're not armed, are you?
不尽然 比尔
Not really, Bill.
我只有一把防身用的小枪 你应该不会看在眼里吧?
Got a Peacemaker, but that wouldn't worry you, would it?
只要看不到 听不到就没事 对吧?
If you don't see it. Or most particularly, if you don't hear it.
恐怕不行 鲍伯
I'm afraid so, Bob.
我不喜欢镇上有人携带武器
I don't like firearms around.
年轻人 好好照顾我的枪
Be very careful with it, sonny.
查理 去看看布夏先生带了些什么书
See what kind of books Mr. Beauchamp is packing here.
小心别踩到尿
Make sure you don't get wet.
他说的是实话 小比尔
No shit. Little Bill
他袋子里只有文具和这本书
All he's got here is writing stuff and this here book.
"死亡之鸭"?
The Duck of Death?
是公爵
Duke.
"公爵"
The Duke.
祝各位午安
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
鲍伯 那把点三二的手枪也交出来
I'll have that.32, Bob.
小比尔
Now, Little Bill.
这样我就得任凭敌人处置了
You will leave me at the mercy of my enemies.
敌人?
Enemies?
你又在谈女王的事了?
You been talking about the queen again?
今天是美国国庆日耶
On Independence Day?
鲍伯 你大概以为我在踢你
I guess you think I'm kicking you.
事实不然
But it ain't so!
我是君子动口不动脚
What I'm doing is talking!
听到了吗?
You hear?
就像我跟堪萨斯那些坏蛋动口一样
Talking to all them villains down there in Kansas!
就像我跟密苏里那些坏蛋动口一样
To all those villains in Missouri!
还有...
And all those villains...
夏安那些坏蛋
...down in Cheyenne!
我要说的是那些妓女根本没有黄金
I'm telling them there ain't no whore's gold!
就算有 他们最好也别想动歪念头
Even if there was, they wouldn't want to come looking for it...anyhow!
你们在看什么?
What are you all looking at?
快滚 滚开
Go on! Get out of here! Do
回去做自己的事
Mind your own business!
威尔
Will
你有进过城吗?
You ever go into town?
偶尔
On occasion.
去卖猪或去买补给品
To sell a hog, pick up supplies.
不是 我是说去找女人
I mean, to get yourseIf a woman?
没有 我没去找过女人
No, I never go into town for that.
像我这样的男人...
A man like me?
我要找女人非得掏腰包不可
Only woman a man like me could get is one he'd have to pay for.
掏钱买别人的灵肉是不对的
That ain't right, buying flesh.
克劳蒂雅也不会希望我做这种事
Claudia, rest her soul, wouldn't ever want me doing that.
毕竟我都当爸爸了
Me being a father and all.
难不成你都用手解决?
You just use your hand?
其实我并不怀念做爱的滋味
I don't miss it all that much.
可恶 有人对咱们开枪
Goddamn, somebody's shooting at us!
该死 你中弹了吗?
Did he hit you?
没有 我从马背上摔下来时撞到头了
I bumped my head falling off my horse.
他好像不是对我们开枪
Ain't shooting at us no more.
他瞄准的好像是前面
Shooting way over yonder.
他在射那个
What the hell's he shooting at over there?
真想不透
Beats the hell out of me.
我们是不是闯进别人的田了?
You don't reckon we're in somebody's field?
这里好像没什么作物
I didn't see nothing planted.
又开始打我们了
Shooting at us again.
他根本是四面八方乱打一气
He's shooting at the whole horizon.
等等 你会暴露我们的位置
Wait! You'll mark us!
小子
Hey, Kid!
小子? 对我们开枪的是那小子?
That's the Kid shooting at us?
小子 是我 威尔莫尼
Kid, it's me! Will Munny!
小子为什么要对我们开枪?
What the hell's he shooting at us for?
是你吗?
That you?
对 是我
Yeah, that's me!
不要再对我们开枪了 听到没?
Don't go shooting at us no more! You hear me?
跟你一起来的人是谁?
Who the hell you got with you, Will?
是我的老伙伴 奈德罗根
It's Ned Logan, my old partner!
不要再对我们开枪了 听到没?
Don't go shooting at us, you hear?
我们先去牵马再过来找你
We're gonna collect our horses and come on over there.
你不会开枪吧?
You ain't going to shoot now, are you?
不会
I ain't!
我找了一英哩才找到我的马
Chased that horse a damn mile.
- 你干嘛开枪打我们? - 我以为你们在跟踪我
- What was you shooting at us for? - I thought you was following me.
我是在跟踪你 你说若我改变心意...
We was following you. You said if I changed my mind...
我可没叫你带人来
Wasn't nothing said about no partner.
这是奈德罗根
This here's Ned Logan.
他是比特瑟豪的侄子库费小子
This here's the Schofield Kid, nephew to Pete Sothow.
我看到有人跟踪我 我还以为你们是来杀我的
I seen two fellows following me. My guess is you come to kill me.
我们没说过要找别人来参一脚
We never talked about no other fellow.
对方有两个人 咱们三个人一起上 免得他们有帮手
There's two cowboys. Better there's three of us, if they got friends.
我自己就能撂倒那两个牛仔 不用三个人一块儿上
I can take care of them two cowboys myself. It don't take three.
奈德是个百步穿杨的神枪手
Ned's an awful good shot with a rifle. Hit a bird in the eye flying.
至少比你高明 小子
Better than you, anyhow.
- 你的枪法逊毙了 - 别碰我的来福枪
- You wasn't even coming close. - Get your hands off my rifle.
我只是想帮你检查一下 说不定弯了
Thought I'd check it for you. Thought maybe something was bent.
我的枪...没有弯
It ain't bent.
你刚刚根本是乱打一气
You were shooting all over creation!
你那份要跟他对分吗?
You'll share your haIf with him?
我觉得三个人平分比较好
I figured three ways.
错了
You figured wrong.
抱歉浪费你的时间 奈德
Sorry I wasted your time, Ned.
你要跟他一起走?
You going back with him?
他是我的伙伴
He's my partner.
他不去我也不去
He don't go, I don't go.
三个人能拿多少钱?
What's it come to, three ways?
可恶!
Shit!
你在抱怨什么?
What the hell are you pissing on about?
你在看什么?
What are you looking at?
什么看什么?
Looking at?
云 小子
Clouds, Kid.
他在看远方的乌云 暴风雨就快来了
He's looking at them clouds on account of we got a storm coming at our ass.
我也看到了
Hell, I seen them.
你改变心意是明智之举
You was smart to change your mind.
我是个神枪手
I'm a real good shot with this rifle.
看到那只老鹰了吗?
See that hawk up here?
我一枪就能打中牠
I could hit it with one shot.
我也能 但我不想浪费子弹
Hell, I could hit it, too, if I didn't mind wasting a shot.
天上根本没有老鹰 小子
There ain't no hawk, Kid.
你根本是个睁眼瞎子 对吧?
You can't see for shit, can you?
看到你的水壶了吗?
See your canteen?
你能看多远?
How far can you see?
够远了
Far enough.
- 咱们这次去怀俄明可不是要打水壶的 - 多远? 一百码? - 不止
- We ain't going to shoot canteens! - How far? 100 yards? - More.
- 你看到前面那棵小橡树了吗? - 操你的
- Can you see that scrub oak yonder? - Fuck you.
- 他根本是个瞎子 威尔 - 我不是瞎子 浑蛋!
- He's blind, Will! - I ain't blind, you asshole!
别吵了
Hold it!
小子 你能看多远? 五十码?
How far can you see, Kid? 50 yards?
那当然 威尔
You bet your ass I can see 50 yards, Will.
我的视力要毙了这个王八蛋绰绰有余
I can see well enough to shoot this son of a bitch in front of me.
等等...
Hold on.
听到没 奈德?
Hear that, Ned?
小子能看五十码 那很好啊
Kid can see 50 yards. Fine.
天啊
Jesus.
看得到五十码外的东西就够了 咱们走吧
50 yards'll do just fine. Now let's move out.
鲍伯 他们似乎都是狠角色
They look like real hard cases, Bob.
你把他们七个全杀了吗?
Did you kill all seven of them dead?
还是其中几个只是挂彩?
Or did you just wing some of them?
封面上这家伙是你?
That is you there embalmed on the cover?
"死亡鸭子"
The Duck of Death?
是公爵 "死亡公爵"
The Duke. The Duke of Death.
你的枪法的确不错 但是一次打死七个? 真赞
You always were a genius with a pistol, but seven of them? Boy!
而且还保护了那个女人 你是怎么办到的?
Protecting that woman and all that. How the hell do you do that?
咱们写书的难免会渲染一下
It's generally considered desirable in the publishing business to take a certain...
言过其实
...liberty when you're depicting the cover scene...
好剌激销售量
...for reasons involving the marketplace.
布夏先生 我看了之后发现 文字叙述和图片差不多
From what I read, the writing's not that much different than the picture.
戴吉特先生 我人格保证
I can assure you, Mr. Daggett...
书中的记载都是根据目击证人的描述
...that the events described are taken from the accounts of eyewitnesses.
- 目击证人? - 是的
- Eyewitnesses? - Yes, sir.
你是说鸭子本人吧?
Like the Duck himself, I guess.
是公爵
The Duke.
我说是鸭子
Duck, I says.
鸭子说道"你破坏了这名美女的名节"
"'You have insulted the honor of this beautiful woman, Corcoran'"said the Duck.
"我要你道歉"
"'You must apologize.'
但是双枪科克兰根本听不进去
"But Two-Gun Corcoran would have none of it.
他边口不择言的乱骂边拔枪
"And cursing, he reached for his pistoIs and would have killed him...
但是鸭子的动作更快 滚烫的子弹从冒烟的枪管疾射而出
"...but the Duck was faster and hot lead blazed from his smoking six-guns."
我认为这样的记载相当详实
See, I consider that to be an accurate depiction of events.
当然我忍不住小小的卖弄了文采
There is a certain poetry to the language which I couldn't resist.
布夏先生 英格兰鲍伯杀死科克兰那晚
I was in the Blue Bottle Saloon in Wichita...
我也在威奇塔蓝瓶沙龙
...the night that English Bob killed Corky Corcoran.
我可没看到你
I didn't see you there.
没有女人
Nor no woman.
也没有双枪侠
Nor two-gun shooters.
跟你写的差了十万八千里
Nor none of this.
- 你当时在场? - 对
- You were there? - Yeah, I was there.
首先...
First off...
科克兰从来不带两把枪 不过他实在该这么做
...Corky never carried two guns, though he should have.
别人都叫他双枪科克兰
He was called Two-Gun Corcoran.
这点倒是没错
A lot of folks did call him Two-Gun.
但那不是因为他带了两把枪
But not because he was sporting two pistols.
而是因为他那话儿又粗又长
Because he had a dick that was so big...
比他的枪管还长
...it was longer than the barrel on his Walker Colt.
他唯一做错的就是上了
The only insulting he ever did was stick that thing of his...
英格兰鲍伯垂涎三尺的法国女人
...into a French lady English Bob was kind of sweet on.
那天晚上科克兰走进蓝瓶酒吧
The night that Corky walked into the Blue Bottle...
还搞不清状况鲍伯就对他放冷枪
...before he knows what's happening, Bob takes a shot at him!
但鲍伯烂醉如泥 没打中
And misses, 'cause he's damn drunk.
科克兰大惊之下下了一招错棋
That bullet whizzing by panicked Corky, and he did the wrong thing.
他匆忙拔枪 结果打掉自己的脚趾
He went for his gun in such a hurry, he shot his toe.
这时候鲍伯
Meantime, Bob here...
鲍伯趁机瞄准科克兰又开了一枪
...he's aiming real good and squeezes off another...
但又没打中 因为他实在喝得太醉了
...but he misses, 'cause he's still so damn drunk!
反而打中吧台上的昂贵镜子
He hits this $1,000 mirror over the bar.
这下死亡鸭子死定了
The Duck of Death is as good as dead...
因为科克兰已经回过神来
...because Corky does it right.
他小心的瞄准
He aims real careful.
好整以暇...
No hurry...
他的枪却走火爆炸
The Walker CoIt blew up in his hand...
他那款枪常常发生这种事
...which was a failing common to that model.
若科克兰有两把枪防身 他会作战到最后一刻
If old Corky had had two guns instead of just a big dick...he would've been there to the end to defend himself.
等等...
Wait a minute.
你是说英格兰鲍伯偷袭他...
English Bob killed him when he didn't even have...
鲍伯可不愿意等科克兰再长出一只手来
Bob wasn't going to wait for Corky to grow a new hand.
他慢吞吞的走过去...
No, he just walked over there real slow...
因为他醉了
...'cause he's drunk...
一枪打中科克兰的肝脏
...and shot him right through the liver.
这些石头顶得我的背好难过
I don't like rocks on my dad-gum back.
- 我好想念我的床 - 你昨晚就说过了
- I sure do miss my bed. - You said that last night.
我昨晚说我想念我老婆 今天我只想念我的那张床
Last night I said I missed my wife. Tonight I just miss my dad-gum bed!
我想接下来你就要想念你家的屋顶了吧? 可恶
You'll miss your dad-gum roof here in a while, I suppose.
威尔?
Say, Will?
杰克森郡那件事真的发生过吗?
That business up in Jackson County...that really happen?
真的跟他们说的一样吗?
I mean the way they say it happened?
哪件事?
What business?
说有两名副警长用来福枪指着你
On how there's two deputies up close, pointing their rifles right at you.
你被逼得无处可逃
Got you dead to rights.
但你拔出手枪毙了他们两个
You pulled out your pistol and blew them both to hell.
自己只受了皮肉伤
Only took a scratch yourself.
比特叔说他从来没有看过 像你这样能杀出一条血路的人
Uncle Pete says he never seen nothing like it, shooting your way out of that scrape.
我不记得了
Well, I don't recollect.
你不记得了?
You don't recollect?
对
That's right.
奈德...
Say, Ned
你杀过多少人?
how many men you kill?
你不回答我的问题吗?
Ain't you going to answer the question?
关你什么事?
What the hell's that to you?
我总得知道自己同伴的底细 碰上麻烦时 心里也有个数
I got to know what kind of fellow I'm riding with, case we get into a scrape.
你杀过多少人 小子?
How many men you killed, Kid?
五个
Five.
多少个?
How many?
五个
Five.
我杀过五个人
I done killed five of them.
其中包括一个拿刀砍我的墨西哥人
That's including a Mexicanwho come at me with a knife.
你闭嘴 好好休息一下
Why don't you shut up? Get some rest.
你们这两个老家伙怪透了
You boys areas crotchety as a couple of old hens.
这样说起来
Actually
科克兰先生拔枪比鸭子...
Mr. Corcoran was faster on the drawthan the Duck
英格兰鲍伯快多了
Than English Bob?
快?
Faster?
快就是他的致命伤
Faster was his mistake.
要是他没有急 就不会打掉自己的脚趾
If he hadn't rushed,he wouldn't have shot himseIf in the toe.
而是一枪毙了鲍伯
He would've killed old Bob.
听着 孩子...
Look, son.
大家都以为拔枪拔得快就是神枪手
Being a good shot,and being quick with a pistol
拔枪快是很不错 但是头脑冷静更重要
don't do no harm, but it don't mean muchnext to being cool-headed.
处变不惊的人才不会发生危险
A man who'll keep his head,not get rattled under fire
就如他不会杀了你一样
like as not he'll kill you.
若另一个人拔枪更快...
But if the other fellow is quicker
越急的人越容易失手
Then he'll be hurrying and he'll miss.
看
Look here.
照这种拔枪速度 我连十英尺外的东西都打不到
That's about as fast as I can draw, aimand hit anything more than 10 feet away.
除非目标是一座谷仓
'Less it's a barn.
若他没有失手呢?
But if he doesn't miss?
那他就会杀你
He'll kill you.
所以像鲍伯这种危险人物才会这么少
That's why there's so fewdangerous men around like old Bob.
还有像我这样的人
Like me.
开枪打人并不容易 特别是当对方也会还手的时候
It ain't so easy to shoot a man,especially if he's shooting back.
有些人会被吓得慌了手脚
That'll just flat rattle some folks.
- 我给你看样东西 - 等一下
- Let me show you something. - Just a minute.
你看等一下
Look here.
拿去
Take that.
拿去嘛
Take it.
这是钥匙
There's the key.
你只要开枪
All you gotta do is shoot me
打死我就能和鲍伯离开这里
and you and Bob can just ride onout of here, free as birds.
- 有子弹吗? - 没子弹就没用了
- Is it loaded? - Wouldn't do any good if it wasn't.
你得先开保险
First, you've got to cock it.
开保险
Go on, cock it.
瞄准
Now you gotta point it.
Go on. Point it.
现在只要扣扳机就行了
Now all you gotta do is pull the trigger,mister.
很热吧?
Hot, ain't it?
你手指没有扣在扳机上
Your finger wasn't even on the trigger.
万一...
What if
万一我把枪给他呢?
What if I gave it to him?
给啊
Give it to him.
你该不会...
You don't really want me
把枪给他
Give it to him.
布夏先生 他好像不想要了
I guess he don't want it, Mr. Beauchamp.
你不拿是对的
You were right not to take it, Bob.
否则我会杀了你
I would have killed you.
布夏先生 天降甘霖正是时候
We could use some rain.
你这匹成事不足败事有余的臭马
You stupid, goddamn, pig-fucking whore!
抱歉 马儿
Sorry, horse.
我带酒原本是为了开庆公宴
I brung this alongfor when we kill them fellows.
不妨现在先喝两口
Figured we could use some now.
我就免了 我不喝酒
Not me. I don't touch it no more.
别这么固执 现在在下雨耶
Come on, Will. It's raining.
我知道在下雨 你拿去给小子喝
I know it's raining! Give some to the Kid.
你认为那小子真的杀过五个人?
You think that Kid really killed five men?
没有
No.
他昨晚说有两个副警长偷袭你和比特
When you talked of the time them deputieshad the drop on you and Pete
我记得你杀了三个人不是两个人
I remember there wasthree men you shot, not two.
我已经改了 奈德
I ain't like that no more, Ned!
我不再是那个嗜杀成性的傻瓜
I ain't no crazy killing fool.
你仍然认为杀那两个牛仔易如反掌?
Still think it's gonna be easyto kill them cowboys?
只要我们不先被淹死就行
If we don't drown first.
把钥匙交给车掌
Give these keys to the conductor.
告诉他一离开本郡就帮鲍伯开手拷
Tell him he can loose Bob's cuffsas soon as he's outside the county.
我的枪呢?
Got my pistols?
你应该知道吧 鲍伯?
I guess you know, Bob, that
下次被我碰见我一定会自卫开枪杀了你
if I see you again I'll just shootand figure it's self-defense.
我没有偷走你的传记作家
I didn't steal your biographer!
他是自愿留下的
He's staying on his own account!
他去死我也不管
He can go stuff himseIf as well, can't he?
我祝你们全部得瘟疫死翘翘
A plague on the whole stinking lot of you!
你们这些目无王法的人渣
Without moraIs or laws!
你们这些妓女不守法 没有荣誉感...
And, all you whores, you got no laws! You got no honor!
难怪你们全都跑到美国来
It's no wonderyou all emigrated to America!
因为英国才不要你们这些人渣呢
They wouldn't have you in England!
你们全都是野蛮人
You're a lot of savages!
我诅咒你们这些该死的野蛮人
You're all a bunch of bloody savages! A curse on you!
在小比尔修理那个英国人之后
Nobody's going to come
不会有人敢来的
after what Little Bill doneto that Englishman.
荻莱菈 桌子脏死了 你还不去清?
Delilah, can't you get them tables clean?
把脸遮起来说不定会有人想上你 你就不用当女佣了
Cover your face, somebody might hump youand you wouldn't have to clean.
遮脸那种东西叫什么来着?
What do they call those face covers?
面纱
A veil.
对 去搞个面纱来
Yeah. Get a veil!
要下雨了
Rain's coming.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
你确定?
Sure?
你还好吧 威尔?
You all right, Will?
艾莉丝 有人找你
There's a fellow asking for you.
今晚? 不是开玩笑吧?
Tonight? You ain't joshing?
这边请 先生
This way, mister.
风大雨大的还逛窑子八成是色欲熏心
Must be randy as hellto come out in this shit.
他说"不 你错了 小比尔"
"No, no! You're wrong,Little Bill! " he said.
"是小写的J 不是大写"
"That's not a curly J. That's a bobbed J! "
被他偷改过 我跟他说
He had changed it over. And I said to him:
"吉姆 你这个说谎的偷马贼"
"Jim, you're a liar and a horse thief! "
他发现没有人愿意帮他
He saw the rest of themwouldn't help him none.
就开始大哭大闹
Of course he started cryingand sobbing and just carrying on.
他说"求求你不要杀我 比尔..."
He said, "God, please don't kill me, Bill!
"求求你不要杀我"
"Please don't kill me! "
我说"吉姆 你这样太恶心了..."
I said, "Jim, It makes me sick"
把窗户打开
Open the window.
"你带着两把手枪和一把来福枪"
"to see a man carryingtwo pistoIs and a Henry rifle
"居然像个哭娃娃一样"
"and crying like a damn baby."
所以你杀了他?
So, you killed him?
没有
No.
但我实在该杀他的
But I should have.
我受不了他们那种人
I can't abide them kind.
他们一天到晚在酒馆里出没
You see them in the taverns.
流浪汉和烂醉如泥的车夫
Tramps and drunk teamsters
疯狂的矿工
and crazed miners.
拿着手枪耀武扬威自以为是老大
Sporting their pistolsand acting like they was bad men.
但是他们既没种又没格
But without any sand or character.Not even any bad character.
我不喜欢杀手
I do not like assassins.
也不喜欢没格的人
Or men of low character.
像你朋友英格兰鲍伯那样
Like your friend English Bob.
鲍伯不是懦夫
But Bob was no coward, you know.
他不会在你面前哭哭啼啼
He wouldn't go up to your faceand cry and carry on like that
警长 我...
Sheriff
可恶 我没有水桶了
I don't have any more receptacles.
也许你该把帮你盖房子的木匠吊死
Maybe you should just hang the carpenter.
什么?
What?
我的意思是...如果吊死...
I was saying that because of theIf you hang
算了
It doesn't matter.
搞什么鬼?
What the hell?
外面风大雨大的
On a night like this!
哪位?
Who in the hell is it?
比尔 我是副警长查理海特
Deputy Charley Hecker, Bill.
干嘛?
What?
刚刚镇上来了三个人 比尔 他们在葛瑞利那儿
Three fellows just come into town, Bill.They're down at Greely's.
其中两个有带枪
There's two of them got guns.
那小子怎么慢吞吞的?
What the hell's keeping that Kid?
他该不会...
You suppose he's up
天啊 威尔 你气色糟透了
Jesus, Will. You look like shit.
- 还记得伊格汉德的死状吗? - 记得
- You remember Eagle Hendershot? - Yeah.
我看到他了
I saw him.
威尔 他已经死了
Will, he's dead.
奈德 我真的看到他了
No, I saw him, Ned.
他头都破了 脑浆看得一清二楚
His head was broke open.You could see inside of it.
天啊
Jesus.
你发烧了
You got a fever.
- 喝杯酒吧 - 蛆从他脑袋里爬出来
- Take a drink, will you? - Worms were coming out.
威尔 我去找小子
I'm gonna go see what's keeping the Kid.
那些妓女八成付了他一笔订金
Must be he's getting an advanceon one of the sporting ladies.
如果我...
If I was to
万一谈定了
If it worked out that I could
我会在上面待一阵子 你大概不会...
take a little time for myself,I don't suppose you would
我想你大概不想来吧
I guess you wouldn't want to come.
先生 把枪给我
Give me the pistol, mister.
我叫你把枪交给我
I says give me over your pistol.
我没醉
I ain't drunk.
咱们这儿法律规定你必须把枪交出来
Ordinance says you got to turn inyour firearms to County Office
不论是黑夜还是白天
day or night.
大概是天气太差所以你没有看到告示
I guess you didn't see the sign,with the weather and all.
没有
No.
但是我没有带武器
But I ain't armed.
你楼上的朋友有枪吗?
Your friends upstairs got any pistols?
他们也没有带武器
They ain't armed, either.
你的酒洒了
Spilled your whiskey.
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
威廉...
William
汉德
Hendershot.
威廉汉德先生
Well, Mr. William Hendershot
若我说你是个说谎的窝囊废呢?
what if I was to say you wasa no-good son of a bitch and a liar?
万一我说你胆小如鼠吓得屁滚尿流呢?
And if I was to say you shit in your pantsbecause of a cowardly soul
我敢打赌你一定会闪电拔枪毙了我吧?
I bet you'd show me that pistolright quick and shoot me dead.
对不对?
Isn't that so?
也许吧
Maybe, I guess.
但事实上...
But the fact
我没有...
is I ain't
带武器
carrying no firearm.
起来
Get up.
这是用来杀蛇的呀?
What's this for, snakes and such?
汉德先生 咱们这儿没有蛇
We don't have any snakes in here,Mr. Hendershot.
枪里没有子弹
It ain't loaded.
火药都湿了...
Powder's wet.
布夏先生...
You see, Mr. Beauchamp?
我刚刚说的就是这种人渣
This is the kind of trash I'm speaking of!
任何地方的酒馆里都挤满了这种人
You find this kind in every saloon in all your prosperous communities!
威奇塔!
Wichita!
夏安!
Over in Cheyenne!
艾比林!
Abilene!
但是大威士忌镇不欢迎这种人
But you won't find themin the town of Big Whiskey.
快点
Hurry up!
知道要怎么跟小比尔说吗?
Know what to say to Little Bill?
你一定要找到那棵松树
Look sharp for that lone pine.
错过就找不到了
Miss the pine, you won't find it.
别管衬衫了 快穿靴子
Not the shirt! Put the fucking boots on!
威尔怎么办?
What are we going to do about Will?
走吧 希望咱们的马儿还在
Come on! Let's hope them horses are still there!
让他出去吧
Let the man out, W.W.
看来他迫不及待想离开咱们这个好客的小镇
He's desiring to leave the hospitalityof Big Whiskey behind him.
下手别这么重 小比尔 她还得帮我赚钱呢
Easy. She's got to work.She's got to turn $1 a time!
若他们只是来搞女人的 为什么会跳窗逃走?
How come they lit out the back window?
因为你把他们的朋友打得七荤八素
On account of they seen you beatingon their friend.
小比尔 他们只是来打撞球的 真的
They just come for the billiards, honest.
撞球? !
Billiards?
难不成他们只是路经此地?
They just passing through here?
他们要去毕佛堡
Going to Fort Buford.
你刚刚海扁了一个无辜的人
You kicked the shit out of an innocent man.
无辜?
Innocent?
怎么个无辜法?
Innocent of what?
天啊 威尔...
Jesus. Will.
奈德 你以前做过这种事吗?
Jesus. You done this before?
做过很多次
Plenty of times.
他的枪一定卡膛了
His pistol must've jammed.
把蜡烛拿过来一点 我看不到
Bring that candle in a little closer. I can't see.
若不是枪卡膛 他一定不会被人打得这么惨
He wouldn't take no beating like thatif it hadn't jammed.
他不会不战而降
He wouldn't give it overand not shoot no one.
他气色不太好
He don't look so good.
他根本没拔枪?
He didn't even pull his pistol?
小子 他不像你这么悍
He ain't as tough as you, Kid.
至少我会拔枪
At least I'd have pulled my pistol.
你拔啦
You did!
你把"枪"从那个女人里面抽出来 跳窗逃命
Out of the ladyand out the goddamn window!
- 逃命是你的点子 我本来... - 我们得走了
- That was your idea! I wanted to - We gotta go.
这么快就走? 我正想再来一次呢
Already? Darling, I'm near readyfor another advance.
- 你还没开工就想尝甜头? - 等你们收工之后再说吧
- You'll use it all up. - No more advances on what you ain't done.
甜心 我们只是在等天气放晴嘛
Sweetheart,we're just waiting on this weather to clear!
我们还需要点食物
We'll need more food!
至少要够我们吃三天
Three days' worth.
三天?
Three days?
- 我们明天就去杀那些牛仔 - 没有他 我谁都不杀
- We could kill them tomorrow. - I don't kill nobody without him.
我们不需要他 咱们两个就能搞定
We don't need him! The two of us could do it.
他只是个落魄潦倒的养猪户
Besides, he ain't nothingbut a broken-down pig farmer.
我们明天早上会带点食物和威士忌来
One of us'll bring food in the morning! We'll bring whiskey, too.
顺便带点药来
And some medicine if you got any!
你听他呻吟哀号不烦吗?
Don't it make you sickhearing him like that?
女士们 别担心
Don't you ladies worry none!
我和奈德会帮你们宰了那两个王八蛋
Me and Ned will killthem two sons of bitches for you!
克劳蒂雅
Claudia.
她不在这里
Claudia's not here.
是你吗 奈德?
Is that you, Ned?
我看到他了
I've seen him, Ned.
我看到死亡天使
I've seen the Angel of Death.
我看到那条幽冥河
I seen the river, Ned.
他有双蛇眼
He's got snake eyes.
谁有双蛇眼?
Who's got snake eyes?
是死亡天使
The Angel of Death.
奈德 我好怕死
Ned, I'm scared of dying.
冷静点 伙伴
Easy, partner.
我也看到克劳蒂雅了
I seen Claudia, too.
看到克劳蒂雅不是很好吗?
That's good you saw Claudia, ain't it?
她脸上都是虫
Her face was all covered with worms.
奈德 我好怕
Ned, I'm scared.
我要死了
I'm dying.
不要告诉任何人
No, don't tell nobody.
不要告诉我的孩子们
Don't tell my kids
我以前做过的那些事 知道吗?
none of the things I did. Hear me?
好的
All right.
他要死了 对不对?
He's gonna die, ain't he?
也许
Maybe.
万一他死了怎么办?
Supposing he does?
咱们就埋了他
We'll bury him.
我不是那个意思
That ain't what I mean.
你想知道我会不会帮你杀了那两个牛仔?
You mean,will I help you kill them cowboys?
我的眼睛不好 看不到他们 但是你可以
I can't spot them myself. But you could.
我打赌你在半哩外就能看到那个王八蛋
That big bastard? You could spot him a half-mile off.
万一我看到他又怎么样?
And if I spot him?
我就骑马过去杀了他
Then I ride up close and shoot him.
就这么简单?
Just like that?
我是个杀手 我以前也干过这种事
I'm a damn killer. I done it before.
我这个杀手比他像样多了
I'm more of a killer than he is, anyhow.
是吗?
Yeah?
对
Yeah.
我还以为你是天使
I thought you was an angel.
你还没死
You ain't dead.
我被一个大块头扁得惨兮兮
Some big fellow really kicked the hell out of me.
我的脸一定跟你的一样精彩
I must look kind of like you now.
你一点都不像我
You don't look nothing like me, mister.
我无意冒犯你
No offense meant.
被那两个牛仔伤害的人一定是你
You gotta be the one those cowboys cut up.
我的伙伴...奈德和小子在吗?
My partners, Ned and that Kid they around?
他们知道你退烧之后就出去勘察地形了
They went out scoutingwhen they saw your fever broke.
勘察地形?
Scouting?
他们到拜提牧场去找他们
Out to the Bar T looking for them.
我在这里躺了多久?
How long I been here?
三天
Three days.
你饿不饿?
Are you hungry or
三天?
Three days?
那应该饿了
I ought to be.
我以为自己死了
I thought I was gone.
我以前很少注意高地景色
I wouldn't normally pay no noticeto high country like this.
但我现在倒是注意到这里的树木
Trees. But I'm sure noticing now.
我以为自己死定了
Thought I was dying for sure.
我帮你把帽子带来了
I brought your hat.
你留在葛瑞利那儿
You left it down at Greely's.
谢了
Thanks.
那个警长...
That sheriff
还在找我吗?
still looking for me?
你是说小比尔?
Little Bill?
没有 他以为你到南方去了
No, he thinks you went south.
你真的会杀了那两个牛仔吗?
Are you really going to kill them cowboys?
大概吧
I guess.
杀了他们还是有赏金吧?
Still a payment coming, isn't there?
你那两个朋友...
Them other two, your friends
已经预支了不少酬劳
they been taking advanceson the payment.
预支?
Advances?
免费打炮
Free ones.
免费?
Free ones?
艾莉丝和阿丝帮他们免费服务
Alice and Silky been giving them free ones.
我明白了
I see.
你也要免费服务吗?
Would you like a free one?
不要了
I guess not.
我不是说跟我 我是说...
I didn't mean with me. I meant
若你要的话
Alice and Silky would be happyto give you a free one
艾莉丝和阿丝会很乐意为你免费服务
if you wanted one.
我就只是这个意思
That's all I meant.
我不是那个意思
I didn't mean that.
我不希望因为你吃苦而得到免费服务
I didn't mean I didn't want a free oneon account of you being cut up.
我那天说你像我是有口无心
What I said the other day aboutyou looking like me, that ain't true.
你不像我那么丑
You ain't ugly like me.
只是我们两个都有伤疤
It's just that we both have got scars.
你是个漂亮的女人
You're a beautiful womanand if I was to want a free one
若我真的要人免费服务 我宁愿是跟你
I'dwant it with you, I guess,more than them other two.
我拒绝
It's just that
是因为我太太
I can't on account of my wife.
你太太?
Your wife?
对 是这样的...
Yeah. You see
我很敬佩你
I admire you for that
对太太的忠诚
for being true to your wife.
我认识很多...
I've known a lot of men
对太太不忠的男人
who weren't.
我想也是
I suppose.
她在堪萨斯吗?
Is she back in Kansas?
她在照顾我的孩子
She's watching over my young ones.
抓紧...
Hang on!
快把烙铁拿来
Get the damn iron!
天啊...
Jesus, fella.
我的天 我的腿断了
Jesus, boys, my leg's broke!
我被困住了!
I'm pinned, boys!
奈德 你去了结他吧
Better finish him.
他还没死? 你没打中他?
He ain't dead? You didn't get him?
他打中那家伙的马
He got the boy's horse.
最好在他脱身之前解决他
Better finish him before he gets clear.
快躲到石头后面去!
Get behind them rocks.
快过去 戴维!
Get over there!
发生什么事了? 他没死?
What happened? He ain't killed?
发生什么事了?
What's going on?
他要是躲到石头后面就打不到他了
He gets in those rocks,we ain't gonna get him.
- 除非我们下去 - 什么石头?
- Unless we go down there. - What rocks?
你为什么不开枪? 到底怎么了?
Why don't you shoot? What's going on?
你到底要不要开枪?
Ain't you gonna shoot?
我不太会用这种枪
I ain't very good with one of these.
戴维 快爬到石头后面去...
Keep going, Davey! The rocks!
打到他了吗?
Get him?
他在哪里?
Where is he?
我还有几发子弹?
How many more shots do I have?
Ned, goddamn it,how many more shots do I have?
两发
Two.
快逃 戴维
Go, Davey!
打到他了吗?
Did you get him?
帮我装子弹
Here, reload this.
- 你没打中? - 我打中了
- You missed him. - I got him.
他没死
He ain't killed.
也许会死 也许不会
Maybe, maybe not.
我打中他的肚子
Got him through the gut, I think.
他会死吗?
You think he's gonna die?
我们杀了他吗?
You think we killed him?
我中弹了...
He shot me.
对 他应该会死
We killed him I guess.
我活不成了
I'm dying, boys!
浑球 早知有今天 当初就不该欺负女人
Then you shouldn't have cut up no woman,you asshole!
天啊 我好渴
Jesus, I'm so thirsty.
史林姆 给我一点水
Give me some water, please!
拜托 史林姆
Please, Slim!
我在流血 史林姆
I'm bleeding, Slim!
给我一口水
Give me some water
可恶 快拿水给他
Give him a drink of water, goddamn it!
史林姆 给我一口水喝
Give me a drink of water, would you, Slim?
可恶 快给他水喝 我们不会开枪
Will you give him a drink of water,for Christ's sake? We ain't gonna shoot!
- 你们真的不会开枪? - 不会
- You ain't gonna shoot? - No.
忍着点 戴维
Hold on, Davey-boy!
我来了
Here I come now!
你们这些王八蛋 不准开枪
Don't you shoot me, you bastards!
可恶...
Shit!
- 他们拿水给他? - 对
- They take him water? - Yeah.
天啊 强尼 他们打中他了
Jesus, Johnny! They shot him!
戴维 忍着点
Hold on now!
你们这些杀人不眨眼的浑蛋 你们杀了咱们的戴维
You murdering bastards! You killed our Davey-boy!
我们什么时候回去?
When are we gonna double back?
过一阵子吧
After a ways.
我不去
Not me.
我要回堪萨斯
I'm heading on back down to Kansas.
我们得先杀了另一个
We gotta kill the other one first.
运气好的话 我们今晚或明早就能找到他
With any luck, we'll find himby nightfall or in the morning.
我们杀了他就能带着钱回家
Then we can shoot himand head on back with the money.
威尔 你要我的来福枪吗?
Want the Spencer?
奈德 现在不能半途而废
This ain't no time to quit.
- 这样你就拿不到你那份钱了 - 闭嘴
- You'll lose your share, Ned. - Shut up!
再见 威尔 再见 小子
I'll see you, Will. So long, Kid.
拿去 你的枪我反正用不顺手
I ain't no good with that damn thing,anyhow.
我和小子会到牧场去杀了那家伙
Me and the Kid'll go over to that ranch and,when we find him, we'll shoot him.
到时候我们去找你 拿着钱一块儿回南方
We'll meet up with you, pick up our money,and all head south together.
万一他不回牧场呢?
Suppose he don't go back to the ranch?
他不会到镇上去 也不会留在荒郊野地
He ain't going into town.He won't stay out in the open country.
他一定会躲回牧场
He'll hole up at that ranch.
我不等你们
I ain't waiting.
我回去看看你的孩子
I'll look in on your young ones.
小子说不分你钱的事你别放在心上
Don't pay no attentionto what the Kid said about the money.
我会把你那份带来的
I'll bring your share.
那小子满嘴屁话
Kid's full of shit.
小比尔
Little Bill
我在上面修屋顶
Just doing some repairs up here.
他们杀了一个牛仔
They killed one of them cowboys.
可恶
Shit.
帕森说他在日初后看到三个人往东边走
Parsons said he saw three men,right after sun-up, headed out east.
其中一人骑着一匹棕色的马 另一人骑着一匹满身跳蚤的灰马
One was on a dunand another was on a flea-bitten gray.
他没有看到第三个人骑什么马
He didn't know what the third one was on,
也许是匹斑点马 但他没看清楚
could've been an appaloosa, because he was looking into the sun.
艾莫斯想知道马匹的粮草是不是由郡方负责
Amos says to ask if the county's goingto pay for feed for all the horses or not.
惠瑟朋说除非我们付钱否则他不卖子弹给我们
Witherspoon says he won't sell usno more.30-30 shelIs without we pay.
用我的狗吧
Hell, use my dogs.
到时候郡方非负责不可对啊
Then the county's gotta take responsibility.
马的事不劳你们费心 肥仔 你到拜提牧场
Don't worry. You get out there to the Bar Tand
叫另外那个牛仔千万不要轻举妄动
make sure that other cowboy stays put and don't expose himself,you hear?
我没想到他们真的会动手
I didn't think they'd really do it.
难不成你以为他们为了搞我们 大老远跑来?
Think they come clear upfrom Kansas to fuck us?
那小子年纪还小
But that Kid, he's just a boy.And the other one
那个好脾气的威尔又是个爱老婆的好男人
Will, the nice one,being so true to his wife
老婆? 他没老婆
Wife? He ain't got no wife.
- 他有 他说... - 他没老婆
- Yes, he does. He said - He ain't got no wife.
他老婆早死了
Not above ground, anyways.
杀人不眨眼的妓女
Murdering whores!
他是自作自受
He had it coming for what he done.
另一个也一样
And the other one, too!
他们两个都该死
Both of them for what they done!
我们抓到一个了
We got one!
警长 我们在牛溪抓到一个
We got one, Sheriff! Out by Cow Creek!
他还活着吗?
Is he alive?
当然 他杀了咱们的同伴 所以我们决定去找他们
Yeah! Bunch of us boysfrom Bar T went out looking on account of them killed one of our own.
结果在往南的路上发现这浑帐
Come across this son of a bitchon a roan heading south.
他认罪了吗?
He admit it?
没有 但他很快就会俯首认罪 他身上带着一把来福枪
No. But I guess he will soon enough.Had a Spencer rifle on him.
那些牛仔有没有毒打他?
Those cowboys messing him up?
应该有吧
A little bit, I guess.
你跟安迪到那儿去 看看另外两个家伙怎么了
Get out there. See if you can find outwhat happened to those other two fellows!
巴克 外面有什么动静吗?
See anything out there, Buck?
当然有 我看到两百个带着来福枪的家伙
Hell, yes! Seen about 200 fellows packing rifles.
他们把这里团团围住说要宰了快手麦克
Got the place surrounded.Say they want Quick Mike's ass.
我说"多少钱? "他们说"五" 我说"五块钱啊?
I said, "How much? " They says,"About five." I said, "Dollars? "
"他们说"五分钱"
They said, "Cents."
我说"成交"
I said, "Sold."
我才不担心呢
Well, I ain't worried!
因为有人保护我
'Cause I got me some protection.
- 他有没有供出另外两个人的下落? - 没有
- Tell you where them others is? - Nope.
没有那人名呢?
Given any names?
他只供出他自己的姓名奈德圆木
Didn't tell us nothing but his own name,Ned Roundtree.
带他过来
Bring him in.
奈德 麻烦你告诉我和布夏先生
You'll want to tell meand Mr. Beauchamp here
你那两个损友的事
all about your two villainous friends.
我很想知道他们的名字和下落
I'll want the names and whereaboutsof those murderous sons of bitches.
- 时机成熟了 - 是啊
- Sure is ripe. - Yeah
待会儿还会更成熟呢
Going to get a lot riper.
你认为他还在里面吗?
Think he's still in there?
没错
He's in there.
他真是个惜粪如金的人
He's holding on to his shitlike it was money.
他在里面
He's in there.
看到他就告诉我
Tell me right off if you see him.
你不会自己动手吧?
You ain't gonna shoot him yourself,are you?
让你杀就是了
You can shoot him.
奈德 你和昆西先生... 另外那个小毛头叫什么名字?
You, Mr. Quincy and...What was the young fellow's name?
伊洛泰特
Elroy Tate.
不对 你刚刚不是这么说的
No, that's not what you said.
不是才怪
Hell if it ain't.
你刚刚说
No, you said:
"来自梅迪森的伊洛昆西"
"Elroy Quincy out of Medicine Hat and
"和来自夏安的亨利泰特"
"Henry Tate out of Cheyenne."
才没有...
Hell if I did.
查理 去把跟那两个家伙搞过的妓女带来
Go get them whores that fucked these boysthe night of the storm.
艾莉丝和阿丝?
Strawberry Alice and Silky?
对 去把她们带来!
Go on and get them!
奈德 那些妓女说的谎言一定跟你的不同
Them whores will tell different lies than you.
万一你们的说词不一...
And when their liesain't the same as your lies
我不会伤害女人
I ain't gonna hurt no woman.
但我会伤害你
But I'm gonna hurt you.
而且不会像之前那么客气
Not gentle like before
这次我会痛下杀手
but bad.
你要去哪里?
Where you going?
- 去上厕所先 - 让我打完这一把
- Out to the shithouse. - Let me finish this hand.
我大便你也要保护我?
You gonna protect me while I take a dump?
- 他们会偷袭你 - 那我放屁臭死他们
- You'll get bushwhacked. - I'll fart on them.
- 我跟他去 - 你可以帮我擦屁股
- I'll go with him. - You can wipe my ass, Thirsty.
管他去死的 这小子没礼貌 死了活该
Hell with him.The man ain't polite, he ought to get shot.
那是他吗?
Is that him?
是他
Yeah, that's him.
你去收拾他吧
Go get him. He's all yours.
有杀手!
Assassins!
开枪!
Shoot them!
妈的 动作快点
Come on, goddamn it!
- 打到他了吗? - 当然
- Get him? - Yeah.
掩护我
Cover me.
- 我看不到他们 - 你开枪就是了
- I can't see them! - Just shoot!
杀了他
Get him!
以前也是这样吗?
Was that what it was like in the old days?
大家骑在马背上开枪
Everybody riding out, shooting
硝烟四起 尖叫声和子弹声此起彼落?
smoke all over the place, folks yelling,bullets whizzing by?
大概吧
I guess so.
可恶 我还以为咱们会被逮个正着
Shit, I thought they was gonna get us.
我甚至有点害怕
I was even scared a little.
但很快就不怕了
Just for a minute.
你以前也会怕吗?
Was you ever scared in them days?
我不记得了
I can't remember.
我通常都醉醺醺的
I was drunk most of the time.
我打了那王八蛋三枪
I shot that fucker three times!
他蹲在粪坑上正要拿枪 就被我宰了
Taking a shit, he went for his pistol,and I blazed away.
第一枪
First shot
正中胸口
I got him right in the chest.
- 威尔 - 什么事?
- Say, Will. - Yeah?
那是第一次
That was the first one.
什么第一次?
First one what?
是我第一次杀人
First one I ever killed.
我说过我杀了五个人
You know how I said I shot five men?
那不是真的
It weren't true.
那个拿刀砍我的墨西哥人被我一铲打断他的腿
That Mexican who come at mewith a knife I just busted his leg with a shovel.
我没有杀他
I didn't kill him or nothing.
今天你倒是干净俐落的杀了那家伙
You sure killed the hellout of that fellow today.
那可不!
Hell, yeah!
我干净俐落的杀了他
I killed the hell out of him, didn't I?
趁他拉屎时打了他三枪
Three shots while he was taking a shit
喝口酒 小子
Take a drink.Kid
感觉好不真实
It don't seem real.
他再也不能呼吸
How he ain't gonnanever breathe again, ever.
他死了
How he's dead.
另一个也是
And the other one, too.
一颗子弹就要了他们的命
All on account of pulling a trigger.
杀人的滋味不好受
It's a hell of a thing, killing a man.
你夺走了他的一切和他的未来
You take away all he's got and all he's ever gonna have.
他们是自作自受
I guess they had it coming.
小子 我们都是自作自受
We all have it coming, Kid.
我一直在注意你 免得你被人跟踪
I was watching you.Seeing you weren't followed.
阿丝和费丝往东走 有两个副警长跟踪她们
Silky and Faith rode off to the eastand two deputies is following them.
要不要帮我数钱?
Want to help me count this stuff, Kid?
- 我信任 威尔 - 你别太信任我了
- I trust you. - Don't go trusting me too much.
我们一起去把奈德那份给他 免得你以为我骗你
In fact, we'll give Ned his share together.That way you'll know I ain't holding out on you.
奈德那份?
Ned's share?
他回南方去了 我们会追上他的
He went south. We'll catch up to him.
他死了
He's dead.
什么意思?
What do you mean he's dead?
他昨天就回南方了 他没死
He went south yesterday. He ain't dead.
他们杀了他 我还以为你知道
They killed him. I thought you knew that.
没有人杀奈德
Nobody killed Ned!
他谁都没杀 他回南方去了
He didn't kill anyone, he went south!
怎么会有人想杀他?
Why would anybody kill Ned?
是谁杀他的?
Who killed him?
小比尔
Little Bill.
他被拜提牧场的人逮到 小比尔
The Bar T boys caught him. Little Bill
狠狠的毒打他
beat him up.
他对奈德严刑逼供 结果奈德死了
He was making him answer questionsand beating him up. Then Ned just died.
他们帖布告说他就是凶手
They got a sign on him, says he was a killer.
布告?
They got a sign on him?
就在葛瑞利门口
In front of Greely's.
他们在葛瑞利门口帖布告
A sign on him in front of Greely's!
小比尔问他什么问题?
These questions Little Bill was asking what kind were they?
问说你们两个在哪里
About where you and him was.
然后呢?
Then what?
有个牛仔跑来说 你们在拜提农场的厕所里杀了快手麦克
A cowboy come in saying you killedQuick Mike in the shithouse at the Bar T.
小比尔为了咱们的所做所为而杀了奈德?
So, Little Bill killed him for what we done?
他不是故意的
Not on purpose.
但他严刑拷打时下手很重
But he started hurting him worse.
让他交代
Making him tell stuff.
起先奈德什么都不肯说
First, Ned wouldn't say nothing.
但小比尔下手太重 他终于开口了
Then Little Bill hurt him so bad,he said who you was.
他说你是密苏里来的威廉莫尼
He said how you was reallyWilliam Munny out of Missouri.
小比尔说"就是69年抢火车时"
Little Bill said, "The same William Munny
"屠杀妇孺的威廉莫尼? "
"who dynamited the Rock Island andPacific in '69, killing women and children? "
奈德说你做了更多令人发指的事
Ned said you done a lot worse than that.Said you was
比威廉邦尼更冷血
more cold-blooded than William Bonney.
而且说小比尔再伤害奈德 你就会去杀了他
And how if he hurt Ned again,you was gonna come kill him
就像你在70年杀美国治安官那样
like you killed the U.S. Marshal in '70.
小比尔不怕 对吧?
That didn't scare Little Bill, did it?
没错
No, sir.
把你的库费枪给我
Give me your Schofield.
为什么?
What for?
- 给我就是了 - 没问题
- Give it to me. - Sure.
你留着吧
You keep it.
我不会再用了
I'm never gonna use it again.
我再也不杀人了
I won't kill nobody no more.
我不像你 威尔
I ain't like you, Will.
小姐 你快回去吧
You better ride on back, miss.
钱你留着 我不要
Keep all of it. It's yours.
那眼镜和花俏衣服怎么办?
What about the spectaclesand fancy clothes?
我宁愿目不识物 衣着褴褛
I guess I'd rather be blindand ragged than dead.
别担心 小子
You don't have to worry, Kid.
我不会杀你的
I ain't going to kill you.
你是我唯一的朋友
You're the only friend I got.
带着这笔钱和我及奈德的份交给我的孩子
Take this money and give my haIf and Ned's haIf to my kids.
告诉他们若我一个礼拜后还没回来 就把一半交给二树莎莉
Tell them if I ain't back in a week,to give haIf to Sally Two Trees.
其他的你留着 去配副眼镜
You keep the rest. Get them spectacles.
你要去杀小比尔 对吧?
You're gonna kill Little Bill, ain't you?
一路上别跟任何人打交道
You stay clear of folks you see.
因为很多人巴不得杀了你
Be a lot of them out to hang you.
快走吧
Get going.
"这就是杀手的下场"
我再讲一次 别再问我了
I'm gonna say this just one more time,so don't ask me again!
参加自卫队的人 郡方会免费请你们喝一杯酒
Those on the posse today got one drinkcoming from the county budget!
昨晚当差的我们再请各位喝一杯
And those who rode yesterdayget one drink for that, too.
等等...
Hold it!
这样一共两杯
That's two!
- 但之后的酒钱就要各位自己付了 听到了吗 瘦皮猴? - 听到了
- After that, it comes out of your own pocket! Hear me, Skinny? - Yes, sir
我们明天一早就出发
We'll pull out early in the morning.
我们要一路追他们到德州 所以大家花钱省着点
We'll chase these fellows clear to Texas,so don't spend too much money.
我们分为四组
We're gonna divide up into four parties!
搜查方圆之内的农舍和小路
We'll hit all the farms and traiIs to make a big circle.
我们一定会碰到看过
We're bound to come across somebody
这两个王八蛋的人...
who's seen these skunks.
这个鸟地方的老板是谁?
Who's the fellow who owns this shithole?
胖子
You, fat man.
回答我
Speak up.
我是这里的老板
I own this establishment.
我花一千块跟葛瑞利买了这家店
I bought it from Greely for $1,000.
- 你最好快走 - 遵命
- You better clear out of there. - Yes, sir
等等...
Just hold it right there!
你是个胆小如鼠的浑球
Sir, you are a cowardly son of a bitch!
你刚刚杀了一个手无寸铁的人
You just shot an unarmed man.
若他想用我的朋友来妆点他的沙龙 他就该随身携带武器
He should've armed himseIf if he's gonnadecorate his saloon with my friend.
你想必是来自密苏里的威廉莫尼
You'd be William Munny out of Missouri
专杀妇孺的杀手
killer of women and children.
没错
That's right.
我是杀过妇孺
I've killed women and children.
只要会动的东西我都杀过
I killed just about everything that walkedor crawled at one time or another.
小比尔 我现在来杀你了
And I'm here to kill you, Little Bill.
我要为奈德报仇
For what you did to Ned.
闲杂人等最好让开
You boys better move away.
各位...
Gentlemen
他只剩一发子弹
he's got one barrel left.
他开枪之后 你们就拔枪毙了那个狗娘养的
When he fires that, take out your pistoIs and shoot him downlike the mangy scoundrel he is!
不发弹! 杀了那个狗娘养的
Misfire! Kill the son of a bitch!
不想死的就快从后门出去
Any man don't want to get killed,better clear on out the back.
我中弹了...
I'm shot! I've been shot!
你没有中弹
You ain't shot.
我没有枪 我手无寸铁
I don't have a gun. I am not armed.
把那把来福枪捡起来
Pick up that rifle.
快去捡起来
Pick it up.
还有子弹
Shells, too.
你杀了小比尔
You killed Little Bill.
你真的没有带枪?
Sure you ain't armed?
没有 我根本没有枪
I'm not. I don't have a gun.
我是个爬格子的
I've never had a gun. I write. I'm a writer!
- 爬格子? - 对
- A writer? - Yeah
- 帮人写信? - 我写书
- Letters and such? - Books.
书?
Books.
我真不敢相信 你居然一个人杀了五个人
I don't believe it, you killed five men.Single-handed.
- 那把是史宾赛来福枪吧? - 没错
- That's a Spencer rifle, right? - That's right
你先杀哪一个?
Who'd you kill first?
"当敌众我寡时经验老道的枪手"
"When confronted by superior numbers
"会先撂倒对方枪法最好的人"
"an experienced gunfighterwill fire on the best shot first."
- 是吗? - 那是小比尔说的 你大概第一个就杀他吧
- Is that so? - Little Bill told me that.You probably killed him first.
这次大概是我运气好
I was lucky in the order.
但我杀人的时候运气总是特别好
I've always been luckywhen it comes to killing folks.
你的下个目标是谁? 克莱德吗?
Who was next? Clyde, right?
你下个杀的一定是克莱德或副警长安迪
You must have killed Clyde,or maybe Deputy Andy
我只能告诉你最后一个是谁
All I can tell you is who's gonna be last.
我不该...
I don't deserve this
死得这样不明不白
to die like this.
我的房子还没盖好
I was building a house.
"该不该"与此事无关
"Deserve" has got nothing to do with it.
咱们在地狱见吧 威廉莫尼
I'll see you in hell, William Munny.
是啊 我要出来了
All right, I'm coming out!
只要看到有人 我格杀勿论
Any man I see out there, I'm gonna kill him!
若有人敢对我开枪
Any son of a bitch takes a shot at me
我不仅会宰了他 连他老婆朋友一块儿杀
I'm not only gonna kill him, but his wife and all his friends
还会烧了他的房子
and burn his damn house down!
最好不要有人开枪
Nobody better shoot!
查理 杀了他
Charley, go ahead. Shoot him!
才不要 我又不是副警长
Hell, no! I ain't no deputy!
你们好好安葬奈德
You better bury Ned right!
也不准再伤害妓女
You better not cut upnor otherwise harm no whores!
否则我会回来杀得你们一个都不留
Or I'll come back and kill every oneof you sons of bitches.
几年后安梭妮雅费瑟太太到霍曼郡
探视独女的长眠之地
但威廉莫尼早就带着孩子们消失无踪
有人说他们到了旧金山靠着卖干货而发了财
但费瑟太太仍不明白
她的独生女为什么会下嫁一个
无恶不做 有暴力倾向的杀手